<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Nick Johnstone's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://widdersh.in/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://widdersh.in/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-16T20:09:35+12:00</updated>
  <id>http://widdersh.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnstone]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ncwjohnstone@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Politics and Anarchy]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/politics-and-anarchy/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T19:25:45+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/politics-and-anarchy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about politics recently.</p>

<p>For most of my life, so far, I&rsquo;ve thought anarchists were delusional. A world without government? You&rsquo;d have to be crazy to think that&rsquo;s a good idea. In my mind, anarchists wanted to inflict chaos upon society.</p>

<p>It recently occurred to me that anarchists aren&rsquo;t crazy, just optimistic. I feel anarchy is about the belief that humanity might be capable of living together without <em>needing</em> a strong system of governance. I&rsquo;ve started to think anarchy might be about hope, not chaos and fear as I previously thought.</p>

<p>This realization came at a useful time. The election is happening soon, and I&rsquo;ve been watching my friends and acquaintances discuss politics on Facebook. The most disheartening thing to me is the division between supporters of the different parties. I&rsquo;ve seen people removing each other as internet friends, simply because they support a different party. To me, this speaks of an unwillingness to consider and understand why other people think the way they do.</p>

<p>All of my beliefs and opinions exist simply because they were what made sense to me at the time. When you drive away from people who think differently from you, you limit your view of the world. In effect, you create a feedback loop that supports your views (the technical internet term is a &lsquo;circlejerk&rsquo;).</p>

<p>I think it&rsquo;s important that we try and break out of the echo chamber of opinions we&rsquo;ve built and have some real discussions. Everyone you meet has had different experiences and will perceive things in different ways.</p>

<p>My advice to you is simple. Strive to see the world through the eyes of others. You might find something you like.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Failing to Forget]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/failing-to-forget/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-05T21:55:28+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/failing-to-forget</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/25009451/ProgrammerInterrupted.png" alt="http://heeris.id.au/2013/this-is-why-you-shouldnt-interrupt-a-programmer/" /></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve recently discovered a useful productivity hack. I found that when I sat down to code it would take me a while to get back into the swing of things. I would have to struggle to figure out where I should start and what to do.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve started writing a failing test just before I leave my work for the day. When I get back to work the next day, I simply run my tests, fix the failure as usual and I&rsquo;m back into my rhythm.</p>

<p>It only takes a minute or two to write a failing test but it saves me 10 to 15 minutes of trying to recover my mental state. <a href="mailto:ncwjohnstone@gmail.com">Let me know</a> if you find this useful, or if you have any useful hacks/tips of your own.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hills of All Sorts]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/hills-of-all-sorts/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-18T19:26:23+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/hills-of-all-sorts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You should watch this video:</p>

<iframe width="670" height="376" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Rj7NEKfjtsc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><strong>Powershop</strong></p>

<p>Earlier this year, I set myself a goal. By the end of 2014, I would be living in Wellington making cool things for a living. I think I&rsquo;ve done it.</p>

<p>I started working at Powershop last week. Powershop is (as the name says) a shop for power.</p>

<p>I was quite fortunate in my job hunting, and ended up with four different offers from Wellington software companies to choose from.</p>

<p>I chose Powershop because they have a fantastic company culture, put out quality products, and treat their employees well. They also met my fixed requirement of having a ping pong table. Everyone I&rsquo;ve gotten to know there, so far, has been really cool. There is a healthy diversity of backgrounds and ideas at Powershop, which I really value.</p>

<p>As a new developer, you join the Dev Train, a special team where you just learn and improve. New devs spend up to three months working on games and other interesting projects to hone their skills before being consigned into production code.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I&rsquo;ve been tasked with making a digital version of the board game, Ticket To Ride. I&rsquo;ve taken the opportunity to try some new things (like <a href="https://github.com/Widdershin/learning/issues/1">BDD with Cucumber</a>), and I&rsquo;m learning a lot. It&rsquo;s such a great way to start a job.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been immensely enjoying my first few days of working at Powershop. I&rsquo;m also really stoked that they hired another Dev Academy graduate, my good friend Tim. It&rsquo;s cool that I get to continue working and learning with him.</p>

<p><strong>Depression and Mental Illness</strong></p>

<p>Lately, I&rsquo;ve been thinking quite a lot about depression and mental illness. I wrote a post recently about <a href="http://widdersh.in/on-being-down/">being down, and how life gets better</a>. Someone who happened to read it sent me an email, with a talk from Ruby Midwest by a developer with ADD and bipolar syndrome.</p>

<iframe width="670" height="376" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/yFIa-Mc2KSk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>It hit home a bit. I&rsquo;ve never been tested for any mental illness, but now I think I will go talk to someone about it. I&rsquo;ve often had trouble reigning in my emotions and motivation, and the more I think about it the more I wonder.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s scary to talk about mental illness since society seems to still refuse to really open that door. I think that Depression and Co. live closer to home than people might realize. Just last week, the internet/world was ablaze with the news of Robin William&rsquo;s death, which appears to have been a suicide. To me, this is tragic and slightly heartbreaking. What scares me the most is that anyone I know could be feeling suicidal, which I probably have no idea.</p>

<p>I think that we need to talk more about mental illness, both in society and within the circle of friends and family. I admire my coworker Chelsea, and <a href="http://chelz.geek.nz/">her blog</a>. I was stunned and inspired to see her honesty about her struggles with depression and suicidal thoughts.</p>

<p>I would love to <a href="mailto:ncwjohnstone@gmail.com">hear your thoughts</a> on any of this. If this section makes you feel uncomfortable, that&rsquo;s fine, it makes me feel a bit uncomfortable too.</p>

<p><strong>butterdb</strong></p>

<p>I was really delighted last Saturday, after someone <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8123450">posted a library</a> I had made (<a href="https://github.com/Widdershin/butterdb">butterdb</a>) on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/">Hacker News</a> and it got up to number 3 and stayed there for a while. butterdb is a library for Python that lets you work with data in Google Spreadsheets as objects. It&rsquo;s like an ORM.</p>

<p>For those who aren&rsquo;t familiar with Hacker News, I&rsquo;ll explain why this made me giggle like a child. Hacker News is the forum section of <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/">ycombinator</a>, a well renowned startup incubator. If your tech business gets to the top, you have either done very well or very badly.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m excited because it appears that people actually use butterdb now. I&rsquo;ve got a whole load of features to implement, and I plan on rewriting the entire library at some point this month. Mostly, I just wanted to brag a bit :).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Being Down]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/on-being-down/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-28T23:43:51+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/on-being-down</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>I originally posted this on Facebook, but I thought I would repost it here for posterity.</em></p>

<p>Someone recently told me something that made me think a bit. &lsquo;It gets better&rsquo;.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve heard that a bit but I&rsquo;d never really about how it applied to me. I thought about how the last few years have been for me.</p>

<p>The last year or so of high school was pretty tough in terms of my emotional stability, and I found it really difficult to talk about with other people. Sometimes I would just feel down, for up to weeks at a time. I wasn&rsquo;t sure if I was just being lazy, or if this was just how things were.</p>

<p>It was even worse in that nothing was really wrong with my life. You feel even worse for feeling down, when you have every reason to be up.</p>

<p>I wanted to post this because I&rsquo;ve only recently started thinking that many other people actually go through this. Someone said something to me, so I figure I might pass it on. If you are having a tough time, if you can&rsquo;t shrug feeling down, it honestly gets better.</p>

<p>My life has been much better recently. I&rsquo;ve been in a much better place emotionally, and it&rsquo;s easier to feel good. I&rsquo;m working towards happiness being my default state.</p>

<p>I know this is definitely a bit weird to post on Facebook, but I think it&rsquo;s important to talk about. Hit me up if you want to chat about it (especially about controlling emotions), or comment.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Academy - the End]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-the-end/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-25T20:29:48+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-the-end</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dev Academy is over, for my cohort at least. A fresh batch of students will be arriving to start Phase 1 in just over a week.</p>

<p>Getting back to normal life is weird. You&rsquo;re with the same group of people, learning intensely for 10-12 hours almost every day, for 9 weeks straight. Dev Academy somehow doesn&rsquo;t feel like normal life, almost doesn&rsquo;t feel real, but it&rsquo;s much more real than normal life in some ways. Everyone is so honest and open. It&rsquo;s so supportive, and you&rsquo;re surrounded by the most incredible people.</p>

<p>The last day of Dev Academy was really touching. We presented our final projects in the morning. Richard, Andrew, Taylor and I had created Skirmish, a multiplayer war game played on Google Maps. I can&rsquo;t do justice to the presentations, so I will post the video once it&rsquo;s available. I was really impressed by the level of quality of each of the final projects, especially from the technically weaker team.</p>

<p>After that, we took our first field trip of the course, and headed up to Central Park. We did an exercise where everyone divides into two parallel rows, facing each other. Each person is in turn blindfolded and walks between the two rows. Each person standing quietly gives the blindfoldee a piece of praise as they pass.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It sounds terribly cheesy. I personally found it overwhelmingly positive to go through. As the blindfoldee (is that even a word?) you hear a rush of feedback, and you can only really grab onto it as it passes. It&rsquo;s more of a surge of goodwill than anything.</p>

<p>We headed back to Dev Academy after that, did some final exercises as a cohort, and then kicked off the graduation party at the Southern Cross. That was a fun night.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve had quite a few people ask me if I feel Dev Academy was worth it. Dev Academy is quite a lot of money, and it&rsquo;s 9 weeks solid booked in your life. For me, Dev Academy was 100% worth it. It was one of the best experiences I&rsquo;ve had in my life. I grew so much technically, but I think I grew an order of magnitude more as a person.</p>

<p>Some people want to see the money though, and that makes sense. I would say most of the people who went to Dev Academy did so to drastically change or improve their career. Almost all of the students started job hunting immediately. Rohan from Dev Academy has been a huge help with that. In the week after Dev Academy, he ran an optional course helping students improve their CVs and interview skills. He&rsquo;s also helped us find and get to know companies we would like to work at. Wellington is starved for tech talent at the moment as well, so things are looking good. I&rsquo;m confident that all of people in my cohort will find a good job.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve personally been job hunting and doing some part time web development work for a skateshop. I really enjoy skate related work, so I was glad to pick that opportunity up. I&rsquo;ve had a few interviews at Wellington tech companies so far, and there a few options I&rsquo;m really interested in. I want to find a good fit though, so I&rsquo;m making sure I hunt around a bit.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got some ideas for personal projects brewing. I have a few left over from Dev Academy that just need a little bit of polishing and they&rsquo;ll be ready to ship. I had a bright idea last night, but the more I look into it, the more I&rsquo;m realizing it would easily be my most ambitious project yet. There is always so much more to learn.</p>

<p>I spent last weekend down in Christchurch. It was really nice to get to catch up with my friends and family (and pets), and to sleep a lot. It helped me to unwind from Dev Academy, and to get back to reality a bit.</p>

<p>I hope this post ties up the end of my Dev Academy story a little bit. Thanks to anyone who has been a reader of my blog so far. If you want to read from the start, check out the <a href="http://widdersh.in/blog/archives">archives</a> I plan on keeping it up. I mostly feel like writing  about technology, education and life, but we will see I suppose.</p>

<p>Let me know if you have any feedback or thoughts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Academy - Week 5 Through 8: Subtitle Undefined]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-5-through-8-subtitle-undefined/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-04T23:45:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-5-through-8-subtitle-undefined</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There was a certain logistical problem I never really considered when I decided I was going to write weekly Dev Academy blog posts. As Dev Academy goes on, the amount of things going on increases. This means that there is not only more to write about, but also less time to write about it. To maybe combat that issue, I&rsquo;ve decided to try a little something different this time. Forget chronology, we&rsquo;re gonna check out some highlights. Less is more.</p>

<p>For the record, I&rsquo;m sitting on my couch writing this on the Sunday night at the end of Week 7 of Dev Academy. As of tomorrow, two weeks remain until graduation. Feels a bit mad.</p>

<p><strong>Learning comes first</strong>, both at Dev Academy and in this post. This is a maxim that has been drilled into us at Dev Academy. If the curriculum isn&rsquo;t working for you, throw it out. If there&rsquo;s something better you could be doing for your learning, do that instead.</p>

<p>I love this philosophy. I&rsquo;ve found I work best in an environment where I can create my own structure. As we&rsquo;ve moved into Phase 3 (the phase where we&rsquo;re treated more as developers, and less as students) we have more of an increased freedom to choose what we do. The first two phases of the course highly emphasized pairing (Pair Programming, two developers working together on the same computer on the same problem). Phase three is now solo optional all the time. I find that independent programming and then pairing on hard problems is a better way to work anyway.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I appreciate the ability to direct my learning a bit more. I&rsquo;ve been hard at work rewriting my website <a href="http://www.nzskatesearch.com/">NZ Skate Search</a> in Ruby on Rails (a web framework that is the emphasis of the Ruby stream at Dev Academy). I originally wrote it in Python with Flask, but it was a bit of a hack job and had no tests. I&rsquo;ve been working on writing the new version in the best way I can. I&rsquo;m using heavy test driven development and emphasizing best practice. It&rsquo;s nice to be able to take this time to work on my craftsmanship.</p>

<p>That project is by no means strictly within the scope of the curriculum, but since I&rsquo;m hitting all of my learning objectives, that&rsquo;s what counts. In the biggest team project yet (whole cohort), we were assigned tasks and roles tailored entirely around our learning objectives.</p>

<p>Sometimes the set work clashes with my ability to best learn. The curriculum licensed from Dev Bootcamp San Francisco isn&rsquo;t as up to scratch as was expected. This is not really a problem, as we (as a school) can steer ourselves. Samson, the teacher for the Ruby stream, consults us every morning as to what lectures or breakout sessions we would like today (if any). These are mostly optional, so we have effectively been left to our own devices.</p>

<p>I have to say that this has enabled some of the best learning I&rsquo;ve seen so far this course. In the last week, Kendall and Andrew created an <a href="https://github.com/kendallflutey/rspec-controller-testing">open source template</a> for testing website controllers in Ruby. Genevieve and Richard have been working on a website to help organize code tips and breakout sesssions. Everyone is up to different stuff, and I think that&rsquo;s really cool.</p>

<p><strong>Working 75+ hours a week is rough</strong>, no matter who you are. This is on the lesser side of some of what my fellow cohorts members have been hitting, so credit to them.</p>

<p>I have been pretty tired for the last 3 weeks. Working so much every week gets to you. It makes it harder to get out of bed in the morning, and then to pay attention when I get to course. I&rsquo;ve been trying to eat well (-ish) and get enough sleep, but 7.5 hours a night seems to be draining me.</p>

<p>I find Yoga to be an excellent way to unwind. We&rsquo;ve had it twice a week since the start of the course. It&rsquo;s optional, and I think only around 5 of us out of 13 still partake. I often find I have quite a sore back, and Yoga really helps with that. I appreciate that it&rsquo;s a nice midpoint between meditation and exercise. It helps me to relax both my body and my mind (as cheesy as that might sound). I definitely want to keep up with it after EDA.</p>

<p>I also try and make some time for mindfulness. Although the Engineering Empathy curriculum finished at the end of Phase 2, Joshua, a teacher, still offers sessions for those who want to partake. Part of these sessions is mindfulness. Mindfulness exercises are simple. Find a comfortable place to sit, where you can find a balance between relaxation and alertness. Begin paying exclusive attention to your breath. Try to notice when your attention slips away, and gently refocus it on your breath.</p>

<p>The point of this exercise is simple. Improve your attention by exercising it. Improve your awareness of your attention by exercising that.</p>

<p>We do this for several minutes. I tend to shut my eyes. You can also try counting to see how long you can go without distraction. This is also a really good way to relax, and calm your mind.</p>

<p><em>writing ceases for a week</em></p>

<p><strong>Suddenly, it&rsquo;s Friday night, 5 days later.</strong> I&rsquo;ve been meaning to finish this post since Sunday, but have only just found the time. It&rsquo;s a week until the end of Dev Academy. If it feels like time has flown through these blog posts, then I feel that&rsquo;s only indicative of real life.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve just started our final team projects yesterday. Richard, Taylor, Andrew and I are working on Skirmish. It&rsquo;s a multiplayer turn based war game (like Risk) played on Google Maps. Final projects are the most intense part of Dev Academy. We coded for around 11 hours today. Richard and Andrew were still going when I left. This is easily the largest and most complex application I&rsquo;ve been involved in building.</p>

<p>We spent around 4 hours planning out our initial vision, user stories and architecture. Taylor (my flatmate and good friend) took the role of Architecture/Tech Lead. Since we want Skirmish to be multiplayer, we have to design the architecture with that in mind from the get go.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/GhvdbPk.jpg" alt="Imgur" />
<em>Skirmish Architecture Planning</em></p>

<p>Richard pitched the idea for Skirmish, and took on the role of project lead. He lead us in developing user stories for requirements. We decided what we wanted to include for the MVP (minimum viable product) and we ended up with a fairly large project still. We want a functioning game with multiplayer, where players can capture other cities and fight. Ideally an MVP is as simple as possible, but even our smallest vision has a lot of moving pieces.</p>

<p>We have until next Friday morning to do as much as we can on Skirmish. As always, learning comes first. It doesn&rsquo;t really matter if the product that comes out the other side is perfect, as long as you learned lots and had a good time. That said, we&rsquo;re working hard. Every member of our team will be working every day until it&rsquo;s over. Lots and lots of coding.</p>

<p>You can check out the code for Skirmish on <a href="http://github.com/rantgames">Github</a>.</p>

<p>I am barely awake at this point, so I figure I should just post this (good idea, right?). There is so much that could be written about that I have missed or forgotten. The last few weeks have been unique, to say the least. It&rsquo;s hard to express in English, so permit some Ruby code instead.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>def how_have_i_been?
</span><span class='line'>  week_adjectives = [
</span><span class='line'>    'tiring',
</span><span class='line'>    'interesting',
</span><span class='line'>    'learning-y(?)',
</span><span class='line'>    'hectic',
</span><span class='line'>    'hard',
</span><span class='line'>    'inspiring',
</span><span class='line'>    'slightly crazy',
</span><span class='line'>    'intense',
</span><span class='line'>    'awesome'
</span><span class='line'>  ]
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  *all_but_last, last = week_adjectives
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  all_the_adjectives = "#{all_but_last.join ', '} and #{last}."
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  puts "The last couple of weeks have been #{all_the_adjectives}"
</span><span class='line'>end
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>how_have_i_been?</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Outputs: &ldquo;The last couple of weeks have been tiring, interesting, learning-y(?), hectic, hard, inspiring, slightly crazy, intense and awesome.&rdquo;</p>

<p><em>Yes Ben, I violated the Single Responsibility Principle for the sake of readability. Deal with it.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Academy - Week 3 &amp; 4: A New Era]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-3-and-4-a-new-era/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-10T23:43:29+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-3-and-4-a-new-era</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a hectic few weeks since my last post. We&rsquo;ve been hurtling through databases, team projects, web applications and more. I&rsquo;ve been busy putting off writing this post for two weeks, but here I am. Let&rsquo;s do it.</p>

<p>The start of week 3 has become a bit hazy now, so bear with me as I recollect. We spent the first few days dedicated to learning about databases and SQL (a language for talking to databases).</p>

<p>We started out by making applications that communicated with the database via raw SQL queries (not fun), then moved into making our own <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-relational_mapping">ORM</a> (Object-relational Mapper, a way to work with databases at a more abstract level, with objects in code). This was definitely a cool exercise, as most people will never write an ORM (because there&rsquo;s no real need to write your own).We then moved from there to using the most popular ORM for Ruby, ActiveRecord. ActiveRecord is much easier and nicer to use than the ORMs we made ourselves, but it&rsquo;s definitely worthwhile to know how it works. Dev Academy often takes this approach, teaching you the internals out to flesh out your understanding. (I had made an ORM previously, called <a href="https://github.com/Widdershin/butterdb">ButterDB</a>. It lets you use Google Spreadsheets as a database, and was originally a joke project.)</p>

<!--more-->


<p>We start off every week on Monday morning with a retrospective of the previous week. As a cohort, we go over how we felt about the previous week. What went well, what didn&rsquo;t go so well, and what we&rsquo;d like to change going forward. We also cover the things we wanted to change from the previous week&rsquo;s retrospective, and make sure that they are happening. There have been changes like improvements to the coding challenges, adjustments of coach times and solo days. I think this is a super valuable process, and  I&rsquo;ve found it novel to reflect in a group like that. It helps to ensure a feeling of participation and change.</p>

<p>On Thursday and Friday we had our second team project. We were told to build something we wanted to build, with some deadlines. We had a feature freeze (no adding features after that) at 3.30pm on Friday and a code freeze at 4.30pm. We were to give a presentation and demo at 5pm.</p>

<p>Our team (Richard, Hannah, Genevieve and myself) decided to build a text based adventure game (think <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zork">Zork</a>). We built the (very creatively named) <a href="https://github.com/Widdershin/text-based-adventure">text-based-adventure</a> game by Friday afternoon. It&rsquo;s fully featured (including fighting, looting and death), but sparse on content. I think 5 rooms made it into the demo we had.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what it looks like to play.</p>

<blockquote><p>λ ruby game.rb <br/>
Welcome to generic text adventure!<br/>
You are in the throne room. There is gold and ruby everywhere. You can see a corridor lined with spiderwebs to the west and there is a small water closet to the east. Make your move!<br/>
There are 50 gems in this room.<br/>
Health: 100, Gems: 0<br/>
> loot<br/>
Health: 100, Gems: 50<br/>
> go west<br/>
Health: 100, Gems: 50<br/>
> look<br/>
Welcome and close the door. Hiding behind the cistern (what are you doing down there) is a box with silver chains in it. There is a small window to the north that leads out onto a firest rife with. The only other option is down the cistern but it appears to be blocked. Where would you like to go?<br/>
There are 3 gems in this room.<br/>
Health: 100, Gems: 50<br/>
> go north<br/>
Health: 100, Gems: 50<br/>
> look<br/>
You are in a forest. You hear a flapping of scaly wings. There are gold goblets and precious jewels in potholes in the smouldered ground. Take some and run if you dare, or face your doom.<br/>
There are 100 gems in this room.<br/>
Health: 100, Gems: 50<br/>
> loot<br/>
Health: 100, Gems: 150</p></blockquote>

<p>(I think we forgot to include enemies in the demo, but they&rsquo;re in there somewhere)</p>

<p>I had a really great time working on this game. Our team worked really well together; we communicated and organized effectively. We had a big focus on automated testing, and I think that really helped on the tech side.</p>

<p>Friday was the final day of Phase 1 of Dev Academy. The course is three phases, with the first covering general development, the second covering web development, and the third being project focused.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still astounded at the immense growth and learning that my fellow cohort members have shown. The problems we&rsquo;re tackling now are so much harder than when we began, and they keep rising to the task. I learnt a lot of what I know on my own, and it&rsquo;s definitely much slower. I think Dev Academy&rsquo;s environment lends itself very well to rapid learning. You have the right mix of enthusiasm, passionate people and resources.</p>

<p>We celebrated the end of the phase with a sweet party, of course. It was cool to hang out with some of the other cohort members and relax, play some games on the project, and have some free food and drinks. It was really cool of the course (via course wizard/admin Rohan) to so generously provide food and booze.</p>

<p>Week 4 began and we kicked off phase 2 (the web development phase of Dev Academy). I know a lot of my fellow students were eager to move away from making command line applications, into something that more people can use and see.</p>

<p>We spent the first few days learning the basics of web development, and making progressively more intricate sites. I found a couple particularly fun. One was on Tuesday, when we were tasked with creating a basic clone of Craigslist. It was a simple listing site, but it was cool piecing it together in a well designed way, and helping the other cohort members build one of their first proper websites.</p>

<p>The other particularly enjoyable challenge was to build a simple login system. I was pairing with Taylor, my friend and flatmate, and he and I decided to take a different tack. We ended up building an authentication system that would let you log in, and then send a link to your friends so they would be logged in as you. Not a good idea, but fun to make and humorous (if you&rsquo;re a programmer I suppose).</p>

<p>On Thursday and Friday we built our third team project. We were tasked with either building a functional clone of Twitter or a Flashcards web app. All three of the teams opted to build the Twitter clone.</p>

<p>We built another creatively named app, Twytter.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/iCC8uPX.png" alt="Twytter" /></p>

<p>Some minor styling issues aside, I was really happy with what we delivered at 5pm. All of the features (like tweeting, retweeting, following, the feed, etc) were functional and complete. We also managed to get in the bonus customer feature, favorite tweets. We were given that feature request late on Friday afternoon, to see how we handled changing requirements.</p>

<p>I worked with Richard, Kendall and Tim. All of the teams were employing a method of building software called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development">Agile</a>. Agile is a way of running software teams that helps rapid, flexible development. It&rsquo;s well used in the industry, and was a great way of running our project. It has nice ways of tracking progress (like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban_board">Kanban Boards</a> and Sprints). I don&rsquo;t really want to go into detail here, so I definitely suggest readers do some reading if they&rsquo;re interested.</p>

<p>We definitely took a few lessons away from this team project. For one, we opted to deal with all of our presentation and styling at the end, rather than alongside feature building. This meant that it was more difficult than it needed to be to piece everything together.</p>

<p>We also made the mistake of not defining a clear scope of what we wanted to build, and by when. We were provided with a bunch of user stories (a way of phrasing a project feature or requirement, like &lsquo;As a user I can post a tweet.&rsquo;) We built all of those stories by the deadline, but as Richard pointed out, we could have dropped a feature in exchange for much more polish elsewhere.</p>

<p>I always enjoy the team exercises at Dev Academy. It&rsquo;s nice to work together with a larger group of people to make something that is hopefully more than the sum of its parts. I have been focusing on taking less of a leadership role during these projects, as I have a bit of a tendency to take that up if nobody seems too inclined. I want to let others take the lead more, and see how that goes.</p>

<p>On Thursday night we had another Dev Academy tech talk. Free pizza, beer and good company included, the entire evening was a treat. This time, Kirk Jackson (Xero&rsquo;s Security Officer) gave a talk about encryption and security, entitled &ldquo;Tales from Beyond the Crypto&rdquo;. Kirk was an excellent speaker, and it was a well timed topic, as we had just started building authentication for our projects. A lot of programmers never learn about crypto or security best practices, so I think it&rsquo;s awesome the the Dev Academy students got a good exposure to it. I know it definitely inspired some of my fellow students to think more seriously about getting into security.</p>

<p>Well, that&rsquo;s about all I can muster the effort to say at this point. Hopefully I can crack the next post out next weekend, but definitely soon. As always, any feedback appreciated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Academy - Week 2: Electric Boogaloo]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-2-electric-boogaloo/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-27T00:05:29+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-2-electric-boogaloo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another week has passed, just like that. It&rsquo;s Monday night, and after a few days of procrastinating I&rsquo;m tackling my blog post for the week.</p>

<p>I spent the early nights of last week hard at work on my latest side project, NZ Skate Search. I got sick of having to check 4 or 5 different skate shops to see if they had the gear I was after. So I made a website (<a href="http://www.nzskatesearch.com">nzskatesearch.com</a>) that lets you search all of the shops that support the scene from one place. I got some good feedback from the skate community, so that made me happy. I started working on the website on Sunday night, and finished it and released it on Wednesday. It&rsquo;s not the nicest code I&rsquo;ve ever written, but it definitely works.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;d like, you can check out the <a href="https://github.com/Widdershin/nzskate-search">source code on Github</a>. Code review and feedback is always appreciated.</p>

<p>At Dev Academy, we spent Monday and Tuesday diving deeper into OO, then into the MVC pattern (for those uninitiated, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_view_controller">Model View Controller</a> is a common structure for building websites). Some of my fellow boots struggled with this at first, but it was cool to see them thoroughly grasp the concepts after such a short intro. It&rsquo;s always cool when you get to see the rays of light shine through, or the &lsquo;Aha!&rsquo; moment as Dev Academy folk say.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>We spent some time on Tuesday evening doing a deep dive session about the Inner Critic. Joshua (one of the teachers and the resident Engineering Empathy guru) gave a brief talk about the idea of the Super Ego, and about ways to defend and ignore pointless inner attacks or criticisms. I found this really fascinating, as I definitely have a vocal inner critic, and the idea that I could learn defense mechanisms against that appealed to me. We did a rather intense exercise where we paired off, and vocalized our inner critic to our partner. I found this a lot more emotional than I was anticipating. It really helps to validate that a lot of the stuff you say to yourself is just a silly attack. It&rsquo;s also good to get some of that stuff out in the open, and to hear that other people have the same sort of worries as you.</p>

<p>On Wednesday (a day where you can optionally work alone, as opposed to our usual pair programming), we were told that we would be pulled aside for a mock assessment. I had mine with Joshua. He prompted me through some fairly standard programming, and then gave me some feedback and advice. There was little given on the programming side, but he gave me some interesting advice about using my time to see how I can best impact the team, and having a (as he puts it) meta-awareness of the social stuff around me. Some of it felt as if he&rsquo;d been watching me like a hawk for the last few weeks, but I feel it was just more perceptive than anything. I also really appreciated how he delivered the feedback. Some of it could have been difficult to stomach if it was laid on me, but he gave it in such a way that it was easier to receive.</p>

<p>My mum also came up from Christchurch for the afternoon for a job interview, so we got lunch. It was good to see her again and catch up. We had a good yarn about some of the stuff I&rsquo;d been doing, especially around the inner critic. It&rsquo;s nice to see a bit of my family in person.</p>

<p>Every day, as part of Engineering Empathy, we start the day with an attention exercise. Initially, this involved a minute of paying attention to our breath. The aim of the practice is to exercise the part of the brain responsible for controlling your attention. The theory is that the more you do this, the more you practice, the easier it is to focus and concentrate on something. The reading I was recommended regarding this is <a href="http://siybook.com/">Search Inside Yourself</a>, written by a Google employee and currently #6 in the Amazon Sacred Texts category. I can&rsquo;t speak to it, but I&rsquo;ll see how the attention exercises go. So far I haven&rsquo;t felt any drastic differences, but we&rsquo;ll see.</p>

<p>On Thursday we started digging into databases. This involved learning about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL">SQL</a> (again for the uninitiated, a language for talking to databases), as well as database schemas and relationships. A lot of this is new ground for me, as I&rsquo;ve never really gone that deep with relational databases. Everyone caught on to the important concepts in databases quite quickly. That impressed me, as some of the finer points of databases had escaped me for quite a while.</p>

<p>Later in the evening Joshua gave a talk about mental athletics. He drew parallels between extreme endurance in sport to extreme mental achievements, like the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Memory_Championships">World Memory Championship</a>. It was a pretty interesting talk, and there was some good discussion afterward around burnout and working hard. It&rsquo;s also cool, as different people from around Wellington come along to our tech talks. Most are in software, but it&rsquo;s cool to meet a range of people. Plus the free pizza and craft beer are great.</p>

<p>Friday came and we had our first team project. We were split into teams of 4-5, and told we could build whatever we wanted, as long as we could do it by 5pm that day.</p>

<p>My teammates and I built <a href="https://github.com/Widdershin/katana">katana</a>, a command line application for practicing code katas. A <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kata_(programming">code kata</a>) is a small programming challenge to aid practice through repetition. katana lets you easily try random katas, as well as to create your own. You can also tag katas, and practice only a certain tag.</p>

<p>This was probably the coolest day of Dev Academy for me yet. I really enjoyed working with my team. We communicated well, and made decisions quickly and fluently. We set fair deadlines and then exceeded them. I honestly couldn&rsquo;t be more proud of my fellow team members to have gone from not knowing how to program several weeks ago to building something I would be happy to ship outside of Dev Academy. We all wanted katana as a tool that we could use, and I&rsquo;m glad that we built the vision that we had.</p>

<p>This was another intense and fantastic week at Enspiral Dev Academy for me. I eagerly await the remaining seven.</p>

<p>Until later (I love ellipses)&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Academy - End of Week 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-end-of-week-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-17T21:33:52+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-end-of-week-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>If you haven&rsquo;t already, it might be worth checking out my <a href="http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-1/">first post about Dev Academy</a></em></p>

<p>Well, it&rsquo;s the end of my first week at Enspiral Dev Academy. It&rsquo;s been a huge week, both in time and what we&rsquo;ve been doing.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/vg0m636.jpg" alt="One of our fearless leaders, Rohan Wakefield" />
<em>One of our fearless leaders, Rohan Wakefield</em></p>

<p>To give you a better idea of what the EDA experience is like, I&rsquo;ll run you through what a typical day at EDA has been like so far.</p>

<p>8.45am: Arrive and check in with my accountability group. This sounds a lot scarier then it actually is. Your accountability group is basically 2-3 other people who you check in with daily to see how you&rsquo;re all going (and to make sure you&rsquo;re all there).</p>

<p>9am: We all head into the lecture room and start the day with some notices, then get stuck in with an Engineering Empathy session. So far we&rsquo;ve mostly been doing looping sessions, which are a really interesting exercise. Everybody pairs up, and is given a question like &ldquo;What is a time you were discriminated against and how did that make you feel?&rdquo;. You then talk to your partner about that for two minutes, while they listen intently. Once the two minutes is up, your partner then repeats back what they heard and what they think you were saying. Then you swap roles and repeat the process.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It&rsquo;s a fascinating exercise, and I found the discrimination one particularly interesting, because as a straight white middle class male, it&rsquo;s not often that I&rsquo;m discriminated against because of my background. I was struggling to think of an example, but I ultimately ended up talking about how I never really felt like I fit into NZQA (New Zealand&rsquo;s high school qualification system). It was really hard to have so much pressure to fit into a system that I never really felt was a good judge of my learning, especially from my family and friends. It was a much more emotional experience than I had thought and I felt like my partners and I really connected.</p>

<p>We also repeated the exercise another day, with a similar question, but this time about a time when you felt privileged. I spoke about how I felt very privileged that my Mum had chosen to pay for my Dev Academy tuition. It was such an amazing thing for me because the money aspect was really worrying me leading up to Dev Academy, and to get a call from my Mum saying she would fund me made me feel like she really believed in me.</p>

<p>As part of EE, we&rsquo;ve also been doing journalling, and another very cool exercise where you had to pair with the person in the room you knew the least, and try and guess things about them like their favourite movie, favourite music and biggest fear, just from what you knew about them so far. That exercise was interesting because pretty much everyone&rsquo;s assumptions were drastically wrong. It feels weird as well, because it plays on the stereotypes and labels you&rsquo;ve put on people, and it demonstrates that quite well.</p>

<p>~9.30am: The day&rsquo;s first lecture begins. To me, lecture is almost the wrong word for it, because that screams having a teacher at the front of the classroom telling you what is what. The lectures we have are far more discussion based, and I really appreciate that. Some of the stuff we&rsquo;ve covered this week has included general debugging strategies, sorting algorithms, source control and more. Most (all) of the content we&rsquo;ve covered in the lectures has been old hat to me so far, so I&rsquo;m very keen for when we get into more advanced topics.</p>

<p>10am: We get cracking on the day&rsquo;s challenges. We were pair programming every day except for Wednesday, which was an optional solo day. The challenges are pretty cool. So far they&rsquo;ve been toy problems to teach problem solving and general algorithm stuff. Once again mostly old hat to me, but it&rsquo;s been very interesting working with people who have a different perspective on programming and problem solving.</p>

<p>Some of the cooler challenges we&rsquo;ve had this week have been making a Boggle Board, and solving Sudoku. Doing the Boggle Board challenge was great, as I was working with my old friend and flatmate Taylor, who is a more experienced programmer than I am. As a result, we got to blitz through it and work on some of the extra credit stuff (like writing an algorithm to check if a word is on the board recursively).</p>

<p>I also really enjoyed doing the Sudoku solving challenge. I was working with Andrew, who is new to programming but has a really extensive maths background. We ended up writing debug code to display the board and decision making for inserting numbers, which turned out to be a really effective way to see what was going wrong in the program.</p>

<p>12pm: Lunchtime. Most people end up staying in past 12pm (to the point where announcements that it has been lunchtime for 45 minutes fall on deaf ears), but I&rsquo;m always keen to get out and get something to eat. Wellington has an amazing variety of excellent food, and I&rsquo;m slowly working my way through all of it. Fan favourites so far have been Sweet Mothers on Courtney place and Viva La Mexico in Leftbank. I am so going to get fat before the course is over.</p>

<p>2pm: Everyone heads back into the &lsquo;delete&rsquo; space (the lecture room) for our afternoon lectures. This week we covered Big O notation (a way to describe algorithm performance), data structures and basic assertions. The most interesting day for me was Friday, when instead of a lecture, we broke up into groups of 6 or so (including a teacher) and had a weekly check-in. Each person has 2 minutes of time to talk about their week. This is cool because you can choose to talk for the whole two minutes, but if you don&rsquo;t the group just sits in silence. I like that because it means you have no excuse not to talk if you want to. It was interesting hearing about the perspective of the other people in my group. Dev Academy can be a hard experience, and it&rsquo;s cool to be able to share how you&rsquo;re feeling in a private space.</p>

<p>2.30pm: Back to the day&rsquo;s challenges, with your pair from the morning. We generally have far more work to do in a day then we can, but the staff have repeatedly emphasized that it&rsquo;s about learning, not completionism. I think that&rsquo;s a great approach, because it means everyone can work at their own pace, and there&rsquo;s no pressure to get through challenges just because they&rsquo;re there.</p>

<p>6pm: We have our end of day check-in. There&rsquo;s generally a few more notices, and then we&rsquo;ll go around the circle answering a question like &ldquo;What was the hardest thing you did today?&rdquo; or &ldquo;What was the most important thing you learned today?&rdquo;. This is another cool opportunity to share and see where everyone is at.</p>

<p>6.20pm: Back to challenges! At this point there&rsquo;s no obligation to stick around, but the doors don&rsquo;t shut until 2am. I&rsquo;ve generally been working until 7 or 8pm, depending on how my pair is feeling or how much I care about finishing what we were doing. After that, I&rsquo;ve usually been hanging out with anyone around, or helping people if they need it.</p>

<p>Sometime around 9pm: I head home for the day, and chill out and watch some TV and do some knitting. It sounds like a crazy long day, but the time has been flying past. I go home feeling tired and satisfied. If this ends up being unsustainable, I&rsquo;ll probably just cut back. We&rsquo;ll see, I guess.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/nnXlKsC.jpg" alt="One of the views from EDA" />
<em>One of the views from EDA</em></p>

<p>Well, if you&rsquo;ve made it this far, congratulations. I certainly didn&rsquo;t intend to write such a giant wall of text, but there&rsquo;s so much to talk about. I&rsquo;ve just got one last highlight from the last week I want to share.</p>

<p>I received a Reddit private message after submitting my first post there. The person who messaged me kindly gave me permission to repost our conversation here, which I wanted to do because it answers a question I&rsquo;ve been hearing a lot.</p>

<blockquote><p>(Anon Redditor)<br/>
Hey, the Dev Academy seems like a cool idea but I am wondering why you would take part when you already have experience and the tuition seems pretty steep?</p>

<p>(Me)<br/>
Hey mate,</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m taking part for a number of reasons. While I had a fair bit of experience, my personal programming has always been shoe-horned around the rest of my life, work and etc.</p>

<p>I view Dev Academy as a way to focus and rapidly accelerate my learning. It&rsquo;s really cool being in a space where we&rsquo;re fully focused on learning (especially modern technologies).</p>

<p>Another big reason is that I was in a boring as hell job, and Dev Academy seemed like a great change of pace.</p>

<p>The last aspect that really excited me about Dev Academy was the emotional intelligence side of things. I highly recommend you check out the video I linked from my post. It explains it far better than I can, but what it really boiled down to was that the thing in my life that I had the most trouble controlling and accepting was my emotions, and the premise that I could start learning tools to do that blew my mind.</p>

<p>tl;dr: love learning, love programming, love making stuff, EDA is good for all of that.</p>

<p>(Anon Redditor)<br/>
Hey man, That is actually really cool! I took the time and watched the whole video. It all seems very interesting and if I had a chance to go to school again that would definitely be a possibility. The reason for the question is I thought you were coming from being a full-time programmer with prior schooling. So I wondered why you would go to a from the ground up training course. But the way it sounds the program really builds a lot more then your coding skills. I will pay attention to your blog as I may possibly be interested in something familiar in the future. Keep up the hard work and hopefully it can change your life in many ways!</p></blockquote>

<p>The video I was referencing was <a href="http://vimeo.com/76762772">Karim Bishay&rsquo;s intro to Engineering Empathy</a>. Highly recommended watch if you haven&rsquo;t already.</p>

<p>I found this to be a really uplifting interaction. I thought it was awesome that he took the time to watch the video and responded so positively. It made me feel good.</p>

<p>There are a few other things I meant to write about in this post, like concentration and breakout sessions, but I&rsquo;ve already subjected my readers to quite a lot, so I think I&rsquo;ll save those for some other post.</p>

<p>Until next time&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Academy - Week 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-14T17:08:52+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/dev-academy-week-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let me set the scene. It&rsquo;s the second day at Enspiral Dev Academy, and I&rsquo;m lounging in the &lsquo;Ctrl&rsquo; space. It&rsquo;s 8pm, and I&rsquo;ve been here since 8.45am. I&rsquo;ll try to give you an introduction to what life has been like at EDA so far.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/fg6OXci.jpg" alt="the view from the alt room" /></p>

<p>Dev Academy is the first ever coding bootcamp in New Zealand, and this is the first time the program has been run. Based off of San Francisco&rsquo;s Dev Bootcamp program, Dev Academy tries to take people at all programming skill levels, and help them learn as much as possible about webdev in 9 weeks. It&rsquo;s an ambitious undertaking, but I think the graduates might speak for themselves. We&rsquo;ll see.</p>

<p>So far in the last two days we&rsquo;ve covered a myriad of material ranging from search algorithms and recursion to a &ldquo;deep dive&rdquo; session about sexism and inequality. EDA has a focus on a well rounded education, and is devoting a good amount of time to what they call Engineering Empathy. That&rsquo;s a stream that focuses on the emotional intelligence side of things. If you&rsquo;re interested in that (and you should be), I would suggest checking out <a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/30/engineering-empathy-tears-and-fears-at-dev-bootcamp/">Karim Bishay&rsquo;s intro video</a> on the subject.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I&rsquo;ve been programming for around 4 years now, maybe 1.5 seriously, and I&rsquo;m one of the more experienced members of the cohort. Most of my fellow boots (meaning cohort members, a term borrowed from Dev Bootcamp) hadn&rsquo;t even touched programming before the introductory phase.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s astounding how quickly everyone is picking up the material. Dev Academy has a huge emphasis on pair programming and TDD, and the benefits show. We&rsquo;re rapidly plowing through the material that a first year computer science course covers, and nobody is missing a beat.</p>

<p>The hours might seem like insanity (yesterday was 11 hours for me, today almost 12), and I thought so too before I arrived. I swore that I wouldn&rsquo;t be doing anything more than a 10 hour day, but the time flies when you&rsquo;re hard at work solving interesting problems with interesting people. There&rsquo;s no obligation to stay past 8 or 9 hours, but the people here are passionate about their learning, and the course material is interesting enough that both nights I&rsquo;ve looked up only to find it dark and past 7 without noticing.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not all been frantic coding though. We&rsquo;re taking part in bi-weekly yoga sessions, run by Alanna from Enspiral. I definitely enjoyed our first session today, it&rsquo;s a really good way to take a break and let your mind and body relax.</p>

<p>So far anyway, Dev Academy has met and surpassed my expectations. The space is amazing, the people inspiring and the staff supportive and experienced. All I can say is that I can&rsquo;t wait for day 3.</p>

<p>More to come&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
