<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Nick Johnstone's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://widdersh.in/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://widdersh.in/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-02T01:29:52+13:00</updated>
  <id>http://widdersh.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnstone]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ncwjohnstone@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/death/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-02T01:24:25+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/death</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been thinking about death a lot recently. Shortly after I turned one, my grandfather on my father&rsquo;s side died while taking a boating exam, a sudden heart attack.</p>

<p>I recall feeling sad about that when I was much younger, but the truth is I barely knew him. I have a memory, or the memory of a memory, of my first birthday. We were in a McDonalds, and I can still see his face looking into mine.</p>

<p>When I was five my father had a brain aneurysm, and while the surgeons were stopping the huge flood of blood into his brain he suffered a stroke. You&rsquo;re supposed to die after that happens, really.</p>

<p>I recall seeing my grandparents waiting for me after school that Thursday, and knowing straight away that something was wrong. I remember riding a toy car up and down their driveway for what must have been an hour, demanding to see my father.</p>

<p>Thankfully, my father is far too determined and stubborn to let a little thing like severe brain damage slow him down too much. You wouldn&rsquo;t guess today if he didn&rsquo;t tell you.</p>

<p>I must have been around eleven when Graham Condon, a City Councillor in Christchurch who worked alongside my mother, died in a cycling accident. I remember shaking his hand for the first time the week before, and being struck by how nice he was.</p>

<p>I was sixteen when in February 2011, Christchurch was struck by a devastating earthquake. I was sitting with my friends in a Subway (food, not transport) in the center of the city. We ran out into Cashel Mall to see shock-waves of force buckling the cobblestone. At the time, I was attending Unlimited Paenga Tawihi, an excellent alternative school situated right smack bang in the center of town.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t remember seeing anyone die. I do remember walking past collapsed buildings, burning and shrouded in dust. I was soon reunited with my mum and my brother and we found our way home. Nobody I knew personally died, but for the city&rsquo;s soul. It&rsquo;s slowly growing a new one.</p>

<p>I had hoped that I had escaped the fear, but a minor quake in Wellington last year revealed the terror lying inside me. The fear is the worst part, and I wish I could move past it.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been downhill skateboarding for 4 years now, since I was sixteen (funny that). I&rsquo;m not sure if that&rsquo;s so true anymore, as I&rsquo;ve only skated downhill a handful of times in the last year.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s the fear that gets me. The fear that my luck will run out and I&rsquo;ll lose traction and hit a car. I&rsquo;ve skated Brooklyn Hill in Wellington maybe thirty times and the only time I came close to falling off was when a friend tried to overtake me and failed.</p>

<p>I love skateboarding, and it kills me that I&rsquo;m afraid of it. Everything I know tells me that it&rsquo;s not about if you fall off, it&rsquo;s about getting back up again. But I can&rsquo;t shake the fear of death on these road.</p>

<p>Just after a year of being into skating, a guy named James died skating a hill named Sugar in Auckland. It was a freak accident, he hit the back of his head while earning a full face helmet and died instantly. The paramedics that were already on site for the race couldn&rsquo;t do anything.</p>

<p>Most people still won&rsquo;t skate that hill out of respect. A lot of people quit that day, and haven&rsquo;t looked back. The number of life threatening accidents I&rsquo;ve first responded to because of skateboarding is too damn high.</p>

<p>My grandfather is dying, slowly but surely. It fucking sucks. Pop, I know that you&rsquo;ll read this and I want you to know that I love you, and I always will. I&rsquo;ll call you soon, and I&rsquo;ll see you at Christmas.</p>

<p>It pains me when I hear people say &ldquo;I&rsquo;m going to work for <em>n</em> years so then I can become a musician/write a book/live my dreams and then I&rsquo;ll be happy&rdquo;. If you&rsquo;ve got an idea of what might make you happy, I think you need to go for it, as soon as you can.</p>

<p>My whole life, the universe has reminded me that I could die at any moment. That fact is now a fundamental of my world view. When I have to make hard decisions, I ask myself: Would I be okay if I died in one month and I hadn&rsquo;t done this?</p>

<p>I hope that I will live a long life, but I assume that I won&rsquo;t. Every day is precious and I spend a lot of time trying to remember that. Plan for the future, but ask yourself how you can make it happen today.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t really have a simple conclusion for you, but for the fact that you are alive and that&rsquo;s stupendously unlikely. Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go With Your Gut]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/go-with-your-gut/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-09T17:57:53+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/go-with-your-gut</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All too often when I&rsquo;m programming I find myself looking at a problem and feeling like I have no clue how to even begin.</p>

<p>In amongst the murky swamp of stress and self doubt there is a little spark of intuition. It&rsquo;s small, and fragile, but all I have to do is blow on it, feed it the fuel it needs to burn. Sometimes my intuition turns out to be wrong. But more often than not that fire shows me the light.</p>

<p>And you know what? I can&rsquo;t ever remember regretting having followed my intuition.</p>

<p>What haunts me is when I find that little spark and then ignore it. There&rsquo;s nothing more sickening than spending hours battling with a problem only to realize I knew the answer all along, if only I had trusted myself.</p>

<p>Now, when I come to a fork in the road. I try not to fret and fray and become paralyzed by choice. I strike out along a path and see what happens. At least that way I&rsquo;m going somewhere.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Random Number Gods]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/the-random-number-gods/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-10T18:44:10+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/the-random-number-gods</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I tell people that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rogue_(video_game)">Rogue</a> has inspired me to write a blog post about privilege, I am generally met with a resounding bu-wha?</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rogue_(video_game)">Rogue</a> is a simple game. You play as an adventurer, descending the 27 floors of a dungeon, collecting gold and loot, fighting monsters and avoiding traps, with the goal of retrieving the Amulet of Yendor and returning to the surface.</p>

<p>Rogue had a few things that made it different from many other games. The first, and the most important, is that when your character dies, you&rsquo;re dead forever. You&rsquo;re presented with a tombstone and some information about your life, but there&rsquo;s no respawn button.</p>

<p>Another crucial part of Rogue is what is known as Procedural Content Generation. In English, that means that the dungeons are new every time you play. Every character you play starts surrounded by different walls, with different risks, rewards, and horrible enemies awaiting.</p>

<p>The third essential part of Rogue is that it is very difficult to win. It takes hundreds of attempts, for most players, before they first reach the bottom of the dungeon, retrieve the amulet, and &ldquo;ascend&rdquo; to the surface. There are many ways to die in Rogue, and a typical player will experience most of them when they &ldquo;ascend&rdquo;.</p>

<p>In my mind, Rogue draws some striking parallels to real life. Your actions have serious consequences. It only takes a single mistake to cause your death. A seemingly strong character can easily get overwhelmed if you make the wrong call.</p>

<p>Like life, you are at the mercy of your surroundings. To succeed, you have to fight and make do with what is available to you, but it&rsquo;s not always enough. There comes a moment in (almost) every game where you find your back against the wall and meet your maker.</p>

<p>It was thinking about life in terms of Rogue when I had an &lsquo;aha&rsquo; moment as to how I could really phrase my feelings around privilege.</p>

<p>My life has been going pretty well recently. At the same time, I see people near and far facing hardship and sorrow. It makes me wonder what has led to our difference in circumstances.</p>

<p>I know that some people like to think that those successful in life fought harder, that hard work and perseverance can overcome any obstacle. While that might play a part, it seems impossible to deny that your start in life makes all the difference.</p>

<p>As an adventurer in Rogue, what you find on the first few floors of the dungeon will have a huge impact on your fate. If you&rsquo;re lucky enough to find a good set of armor or the right potions on the first floor, you&rsquo;ll probably breeze through the early dungeon. You will survive some situations simply because you got lucky and had what others didn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>In my mind, it&rsquo;s the same &ndash; to have parents that teach you to read before you start school. I was lucky enough to have parents that both taught me to learn and nourished the spark of curiosity inside of me. That seemingly small gift early on has had huge impacts throughout my life. If not for that, probably, you wouldn&rsquo;t be reading my blog.</p>

<p>I was extremely privileged to be born where and when I was, and to whom. I think it&rsquo;s important to consider that not everyone is so fortunate.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Politics and Anarchy]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/politics-and-anarchy/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-16T19:25:45+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/politics-and-anarchy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about politics recently.</p>

<p>For most of my life, so far, I&rsquo;ve thought anarchists were delusional. A world without government? You&rsquo;d have to be crazy to think that&rsquo;s a good idea. In my mind, anarchists wanted to inflict chaos upon society.</p>

<p>It recently occurred to me that anarchists aren&rsquo;t crazy, just optimistic. I feel anarchy is about the belief that humanity might be capable of living together without <em>needing</em> a strong system of governance. I&rsquo;ve started to think anarchy might be about hope, not chaos and fear as I previously thought.</p>

<p>This realization came at a useful time. The election is happening soon, and I&rsquo;ve been watching my friends and acquaintances discuss politics on Facebook. The most disheartening thing to me is the division between supporters of the different parties. I&rsquo;ve seen people removing each other as internet friends, simply because they support a different party. To me, this speaks of an unwillingness to consider and understand why other people think the way they do.</p>

<p>All of my beliefs and opinions exist simply because they were what made sense to me at the time. When you drive away from people who think differently from you, you limit your view of the world. In effect, you create a feedback loop that supports your views (the technical internet term is a &lsquo;circlejerk&rsquo;).</p>

<p>I think it&rsquo;s important that we try and break out of the echo chamber of opinions we&rsquo;ve built and have some real discussions. Everyone you meet has had different experiences and will perceive things in different ways.</p>

<p>My advice to you is simple. Strive to see the world through the eyes of others. You might find something you like.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hills of All Sorts]]></title>
    <link href="http://widdersh.in/hills-of-all-sorts/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-18T19:26:23+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://widdersh.in/hills-of-all-sorts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You should watch this video:</p>

<iframe width="670" height="376" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Rj7NEKfjtsc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><strong>Powershop</strong></p>

<p>Earlier this year, I set myself a goal. By the end of 2014, I would be living in Wellington making cool things for a living. I think I&rsquo;ve done it.</p>

<p>I started working at Powershop last week. Powershop is (as the name says) a shop for power.</p>

<p>I was quite fortunate in my job hunting, and ended up with four different offers from Wellington software companies to choose from.</p>

<p>I chose Powershop because they have a fantastic company culture, put out quality products, and treat their employees well. They also met my fixed requirement of having a ping pong table. Everyone I&rsquo;ve gotten to know there, so far, has been really cool. There is a healthy diversity of backgrounds and ideas at Powershop, which I really value.</p>

<p>As a new developer, you join the Dev Train, a special team where you just learn and improve. New devs spend up to three months working on games and other interesting projects to hone their skills before being consigned into production code.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I&rsquo;ve been tasked with making a digital version of the board game, Ticket To Ride. I&rsquo;ve taken the opportunity to try some new things (like <a href="https://github.com/Widdershin/learning/issues/1">BDD with Cucumber</a>), and I&rsquo;m learning a lot. It&rsquo;s such a great way to start a job.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been immensely enjoying my first few days of working at Powershop. I&rsquo;m also really stoked that they hired another Dev Academy graduate, my good friend Tim. It&rsquo;s cool that I get to continue working and learning with him.</p>

<p><strong>Depression and Mental Illness</strong></p>

<p>Lately, I&rsquo;ve been thinking quite a lot about depression and mental illness. I wrote a post recently about <a href="http://widdersh.in/on-being-down/">being down, and how life gets better</a>. Someone who happened to read it sent me an email, with a talk from Ruby Midwest by a developer with ADD and bipolar syndrome.</p>

<iframe width="670" height="376" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/yFIa-Mc2KSk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>It hit home a bit. I&rsquo;ve never been tested for any mental illness, but now I think I will go talk to someone about it. I&rsquo;ve often had trouble reigning in my emotions and motivation, and the more I think about it the more I wonder.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s scary to talk about mental illness since society seems to still refuse to really open that door. I think that Depression and Co. live closer to home than people might realize. Just last week, the internet/world was ablaze with the news of Robin William&rsquo;s death, which appears to have been a suicide. To me, this is tragic and slightly heartbreaking. What scares me the most is that anyone I know could be feeling suicidal, which I probably have no idea.</p>

<p>I think that we need to talk more about mental illness, both in society and within the circle of friends and family. I admire my coworker Chelsea, and <a href="http://chelz.geek.nz/">her blog</a>. I was stunned and inspired to see her honesty about her struggles with depression and suicidal thoughts.</p>

<p>I would love to <a href="mailto:ncwjohnstone@gmail.com">hear your thoughts</a> on any of this. If this section makes you feel uncomfortable, that&rsquo;s fine, it makes me feel a bit uncomfortable too.</p>

<p><strong>butterdb</strong></p>

<p>I was really delighted last Saturday, after someone <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8123450">posted a library</a> I had made (<a href="https://github.com/Widdershin/butterdb">butterdb</a>) on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/">Hacker News</a> and it got up to number 3 and stayed there for a while. butterdb is a library for Python that lets you work with data in Google Spreadsheets as objects. It&rsquo;s like an ORM.</p>

<p>For those who aren&rsquo;t familiar with Hacker News, I&rsquo;ll explain why this made me giggle like a child. Hacker News is the forum section of <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/">ycombinator</a>, a well renowned startup incubator. If your tech business gets to the top, you have either done very well or very badly.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m excited because it appears that people actually use butterdb now. I&rsquo;ve got a whole load of features to implement, and I plan on rewriting the entire library at some point this month. Mostly, I just wanted to brag a bit :).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
